A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, Accession 2000:032, SG 2 FA1405
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, Accession 2000:032, SG 2
1983-2003
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA1405
6.41 Cubic Feet 16 standard letter document boxes, 1 3x5 card file
Arrangement
Original order, as received.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of the RAC.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents
Grants Management office files including but not limited to: Program Reviews and Grant Lists 1983-1990; Program Management Committee files, grant administration files, and associated background papers, correspondence and several financial reports and budgets.
Sound recordings
- Massachusetts Saving Lives Program, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
- Commonwealth Fund-Picker Humane Care Program (Patient-Centered Care Program), 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1-12)
- Commonwealth Fund-Picker Humane Care Program (Patient-Centered Care Program), 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Completed Grant Reports (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Grants Lists, 1983-1988 (Grants Awarded Since 1980) (Box 3, Folder 3-5)
- Grants Lists, 1983-1993 (Grants Awarded Since 1980) (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- Grants Monitoring Program Analyses, 1983-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1-19)
- Program Review - Nursing Home Restraint Removal Program, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- Program Review - Commonwealth Fund-Picker Patient-Centered Care Program, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
- Program Monitoring Committee 1995 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
- Program Monitoring Committee 1995 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
- Program Monitoring Committee 1996 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Program Review - Commonwealth Fund-Picker Patient-Centered Care Program, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Program Review - Women's Health Program, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Program Review - Nursing Home Restraint Removal Program, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Commonwealth Fund Commission on Elderly People Living Alone - Background papers (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
- Commonwealth Fund Commission on Elderly People Living Alone - Background papers (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
- Commonwealth Fund Commission on Elderly People Living Alone - Background papers (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
- Elderly Project - General Correspondence, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- 94-09 - Survey of Patient Exp, with Managed Care (Box 11, Folder 2-4)
- 93-32 - University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill - Analyzing Changes in Health Insurance, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
- 93-73 - Project Hope - Planning a Survey of Managed Care, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
- 2000355 - PDF - Fronstin - The Economic Cost of theUninsured: Implications (Box 12, Folder 5)
- 20000049 - Arig - Century Foundation - Discussing the Major Options for Changing Medicare (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
- 93-71 - UCLA - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- 94-59 - George Washington University - Richard Merritt, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- 94-11 - Dartmouth College, Ann Barry Flood, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- 980467 - Harvard Medical School, Cleary, 1998-2000 (Box 14, Folder 2-5)
- Geriatric Scholars Initiative - Background Information, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- PDF 2000051 - University of Wisconsin, Zimmerman - Documenting the Major Issues surrounding Nursing Home Quality of Care, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Focus Group (Box 14, Folder 8)
- 20000226 - Project Hope, 1999-2000 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- 20000226 - Project Hope, 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
- 20000240 - Alliance for Health Reform - Medicare Plus Choice, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Medicare Plus Choice: Current Issues, Future Prospects - Part 1, 2000 October 23; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 93 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 9951)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research. Digital access copy available.
  Scope and Contents
  Introductory address by Karen Davis followed by a roundtable discussion on the Studies on the Impact of Medicare Plus Choice. Topics include reviewing progress since 1997, troubling signals, industry change, and higher premiums.
- Medicare Plus Choice: Current Issues, Future Prospects - Part 2, 2000 October 23; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 85 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 9952)
  Continuation of a roundtable discussion on the Studies on the Impact of Medicare Plus Choice. Topics include reviewing progress since 1997, troubling signals, industry change, and higher premiums.
- 20000240 - Alliance for Health Reform - Prescription Drug Coverage for Medicare Beneficiaries, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Prescription Drug Coverage for Medicare Beneficiaries - Part 1, 2000 November 17; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 86 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 9953)
  Introduction by Karen Davis and Brian Biles followed by a roundtable discussion.
- Prescription Drug Coverage for Medicare Beneficiaries - Part 2, 2000 November 17; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 88 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 9954)
- Prescription Drug Coverage for Medicare Beneficiaries - Part 3, 2000 November 17; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 9 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 9955)
- 20000719 - Semmel - Analysis of the State Role in Developing PACE Sites, 2000-2003 (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
- 20000439 - Picker Institute- Edgeman-Levitan - Patient-Centered Quality of Care Survey, 1999-2001 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- 20030043 - The Lewin Group, John Sheils - 20-20 Vision Proposal, 2002-2003 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- 20020518 - National Health Law Program - Agreement, 2002-2003 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- 20030125 - MIT - Jonathan Gruber - 20-20 Vision Proposal, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- 990772 - Lewin Group - Lisa Alecxin - Cognative Impairment Report (Box 16, Folder 5)
- 200010435 PDF - Karp-Massachusetts Health Quality Partners (MHQP) - Assessing Patients Experience with Care at the Physician Level, 2001-2002 (Box 16, Folder 6)